SARA KEVORKIAN

FRONT FND DEVELOPER

■ sdkevorkian@gmail.com • www.sarakevorkian.com • 253-332-7341 • Seattle, WA

in sarakevorkian O sdkevorkian

SUMMARY

I am a Seattle-based front end developer that has delivered for a variety of industries including real estate and airlines. I am primarily a front end developer with some back end development experience. My background in biotech taught me the importance of flexibility and the mindset to break concepts down into testable pieces. I am an analytical thinker and love to ask questions, while keeping a collaborative, positive mindset. In my 2+ years of experience I have learned new technologies quickly to meet project needs.

EXPERIENCE

Sr Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle

AVANADE, Dec. 2019 - Current

Notable Projects:

Iuly 2019 - Current

I was the lead FED within a primarily offshore team to develop a new internal employee Sharepoint hub for a large corporation.

I joined the project in pre-development phase, and provided feedback on design feasibility.

Worked closely with design along development, relayed these conversations to offshore backend engineering team, and collaborated on solutions.

Researched approaches to challenging features and created Proofs Of Concept

Delivered Pilot stage in 3 months and was extended into second phase of project.

While on this project received Avanade North America's November "Recognizing Excellence" award

Consultant - Front End Developer, Seattle

Dec. 2018 - Current

Notable Projects:

May 2019 - June 2019

I developed the UI of a workflow app for developers to bring new apps to the cloud using a React components and Python REST APIs.

Guided two junior developers on strategies to create features or fix bugs.

Collaborated with backend developers and defined JSON structure of complex app state.

Worked alongside UX designers to adjust the UI based on client feedback.

Assisted DevOps with setting up config files between environments.

I was the lead FED on a team tasked to create a simpler and more intuitive version of a US airline's internal policy search tool.

Responsible for all features, including search, a bookmarking system, saving notes, and gamification.

Guided development team toward a modular approach to saving policy data.

Directly collaborated with the client on UI decisions.

Took on additional back end work to move the project forward when blocked.

Sr Analyst - Front End Developer, Seattle

Aug. 2017 - Nov. 2018

Notable Projects:

April 2018 - June 2018

As the lead front end developer, I integrated the newest version of Coveo search into an existing Angular/Sitecore intranet site.

Heavily customized Coveo search interface to create an engaging search experience.

Communicated directly with client team to clarify prototypes and requirements.

Identified Coveo component structure for the search page including components that could be used out of the box and that needed customization.

As I rolled off the project, guided a junior developer to finish remaining bugs within a set bucket of hours.

While on this project awarded Seattle team's "Studio Champ" for May 2018

Aug 2017 - March 2018

I worked with the existing development team to solve UI bugs for a Coveo-driven Sitecore website.

I was extended as the sole front end developer, and was responsible for performance enhancement, localization, and design change requests.

Improved performance of business critical property search page by 50-75% - reduced number of queries from 8 to 2 and page load speed from 10s to 5s. Implemented last minute feature request for a landing page carousel in one day.

Web Development Immersive. Seattle

GENERAL ASSEMBLY. Mar. 2017 - June 2017

Accelerated project oriented learning - 50+ hours per week over 3 months. Worked individually and as a team to develop full-stack web applications.

Clinical Research Associate - Molecular Analysis / QC Lead, Seattle

HEMATOLOGICS INC., Nov. 2014 - Feb. 2017

Worked within an interdisciplinary team performing clinical DNA testing; prepared molecular lab for CAP audit

Molecular Technologist II/Quality Assistant, Seattle

GENELEX CORPORATION, Sept. 2013 - Nov. 2014

Performed high throughput clinical DNA testing; managed purchasing and quality databases.

Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2013

Molecular Technologist I, Seattle Molecular Technician. Seattle

Sept. 2011 - Sept. 2012

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

TOOLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React, Angular.js, Bootstrap, SQL, MongoDB, Web APIs, Git/Github, Materialize, Coveo, Sitecore, SASS, LESS, Gulp, Grunt, Akumina, Sharepoint

WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY B. S. Cellular and Molecular Biology/Biochemistry 2011

ABILITIES Troubleshooting, Teamwork, Communication, Flexibility, Positivity,

SKILLS

Organization, Self-Reliance